A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Program and Policy, Health Sciences, SG 3.4 FA1199
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Program and Policy, Health Sciences, SG 3.4
1981, 1984-1995
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA1199
3.8 Cubic Feet 10 document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 20 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
As received
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, memoranda, and organizational materials.
Biographical / Historical
Scott Halstead is a world leader in research on dengue and other arthropod-borne viral infections. He has published over 400 scientific papers and book chapters on many areas of vaccine research and in international health development. In 1990, while with the Rockefeller Foundation, he co-founded the Children's Vaccine Initiative.
Born in India, then moved to White Plains in 1936. Scott Halstead graduated from Yale University with a B.A. in 1951 and from Columbia University with a M.D. in 1955.
From 1983-1995, at the Rockefeller Foundation, he served successively as Associate, Deputy and Acting Director of the Health Sciences Division.
- Officers' Files, Scott Halstead
  - General Coarrespondence, 1984-1988 January- June (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - General Correspondence, 1988 July-December-1991 January-June (Box 2, Folder 7-12)
  - General Correspondence, 1991 July-December-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13-17)
  - General Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Aga Khan University, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - AIDS Seminar, Vector Biology and Control Project, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - AIDS Vaccine Selection Committee, 1989 March 17, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - AIDS Vaccine Selection Group (AVEG), 1992 February 21, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - American Association of Immunologists, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - American Epidemiological Society, Annual Meeting, 1990 March 22-23, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - American Health Centers (AHC) Meetings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1992 October 4-7, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - American Public Health Association (APHA) Meeting, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Armed Forces Epidemiological Board (AFEB), 1991 February 26-March 1 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Armed Forces Epidemiological Board (AFEB), Department of Defense, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Bellagio, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Berkley, Seth F., Memoranda, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Bhumibol Adulayedej, King of Thailand, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Biotechnology Career Fellowship Meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Board on International Health Meeting, 1989 August 23-24, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Board of Scientific Counselors, Center for Disease Control, Meeting, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Center for Infectious Diseases, Scientific Advisory Council, 1989 May 7-9, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 36A)
  - Child Survival Fellows Program, General, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Child Survival Fellows Program, Advisory Board Meeting, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Child Survival Fellowship, Advisory Board, Eastern Corridor, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Child Survival Fellowship Program, Advisory Board, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Chinese Medical Association, 1992 June 9-15, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Defense Science Board Task Force, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Dengue Steering Committee, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Dengue Vaccine Development, 1991 August 26-28, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Dengue Vaccine Development, 1992 August 24-26, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Division of Vector-Borne Diseases, Program Review, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Downs, Wilbur, 1988, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Evans, John, Memoranda, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Gibson, James O., Memoranda, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Goldmark, Peter C., Jr., 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Goldmark, Peter C., Jr., Trip, 1990 January 29-February 13, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Health and Child Survival Fellows Program Meetings, 1990 August 20-21, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Health and Child Survival Fellows Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Herdt, Robert H., 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Hughes, Jane, AIDS, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Immunobiology and Pathogenesis of Persistent Virus Infections, Ken Herrmann, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America, 1985-1991 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Institute of Medicine, Committee on Malaria Prevention and Control, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Institute of Medicine, Conference, Development of Vaccines, 1987 December 14-15, 1987-1988, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Institute of Tropical Medicine, "Pedro Kouri", 50th Anniversary of Havana, Cuba, 1988 December 7-10, 1986-1988, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - International Centers for Tropical Disease Research, 1992 April 29-May 1, 1990, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - International Clinical Epidemiology Network (INCLEN), 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - XI International Congress for Tropical Medicine and Malaria, 1984 September 16-22, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - XII International Congress for Tropical Medicine and Malaria, 1988 September 18-23, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - VIII International Congress of Virology, 1990 August 26-31, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - International Federation for Tropical Medicine (IFTM), Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - International Federation for Tropical Medicine (IFTM), General Assembly Council Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - International Forum for AIDS Research (IFAR), 1990 May 3, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 68-69)
  - International Health Board Meeting, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - International Health Policy Program, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Japanese International Health, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Johns Hopkins University, School of Hygiene and Public Health, Colloquium on International Health Development, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Karel, Frank, Memoranda, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - MacArthur Foundation Network on the Biology of Parasite Vectors, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Management Science for Health, Jon E. Rhode, 1981, 1984, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Mexico, Board of Trustees, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Moock, Joyce L., 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Morens, David, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), International Collaboration in Health Research, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), Plan for Development and Testing Dengue Vaccine in Brazil, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Population Meeting, Barbara Turner, 1991 February 6-8, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Prewitt, Kenneth, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Price, Hugh B., Memoranda, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Project Hope Health Sciences Education Center, Indonesia Project, 1985, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Board of Trustees, 1984-1990 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 75th Anniversary Dinner Invitations, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Secretary Memoranda to Scott Halstead, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Segal, Sheldon J., Memoranda, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Soe Thein, Department of Medical Research Mayanmar, 1984-1985, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Staff Committee on Corporate Responsibility, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Symposium on Hemostatic Fever Impairment Associated with Hemorrhagic Fever Viruses, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Task Force for Disease Eradication, 1989 October 3, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - United States of American Agency for International Development (USAID), 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Vaccine Related Injuries, 1984, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Victorian Health Promotion Foundation, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Vita Proposal, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Vitarana, Tissa, 1991 June 21-22, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Warren, Kenneth S., Memoranda, 1988, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Warren Weaver Fellows, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - The World Bank, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - The World Bank, International Health Policy Program, 1989 March 3, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - The World Bank, Woods Hole, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - World Health Organization (WHO), Yvo Nuyens, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Yale Arbovirus Research Unit, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 106)